

**Email** dmerino2235@gmail.com

**Address** *Ambato, Matheu y Cazadores* 

**Phone** 

+593 987390653

**Date of birth** 1996-04-07

**Nationality** Ecuadorian

#### Skills

- Html
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Programming
- Organized
- Computer Science
- Google Analytics
- Writting
- Tech Support
- Multitasking

## Languajes

• English - Intermediate

#### References

- Edwin Fabricio Guajala Caijo 0983513119
- Maritza Tatiana Nuñez
   Altamirano
   0995251579

# **Danny Joel Merino Chiliquinga**

**Electronics and Communications Engineer** 

Electronics and Communications Engineer with experience in IT and electronic security, skills in the design, implementation, and maintenance of electronic systems and computer equipment. Knowledge in responsive web development with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Teamwork and effective problemsolving abilities. Proactive attitude and results-oriented.

## **Experience**

## • Information Technology Assistant

**Center for Productive Development** Ambato

Oct 2022 - Jun 2023

- Configure and maintain user accounts, permissions, and access in Windows and Linux systems.
- Maintenance and updating of plugins on the organization's web platform based on Wordpress.
- Implementation of a database based on the Google Sheets API.
- Enable network services according to the organization's information needs.
- Implement local networks according to standards that ensure their operation, to share information technology resources.
- Provide technical support to computer equipment and peripherals, following the maintenance plan and organization's policies.
- o Perform software updates and patches on computer systems.

## Console Operator

**INVIN-OSCUS** Ambato

Jan 2022 - Sep 2022

- Coordination of security for transport of valuables, ATM restocking, and offices.
- Responsible for supervision, installation, and configuration of CCTV security cameras.
- Customer service provided via phone, email, and face-to-face interactions.
- Coordination of a team of over 40 security guards, 10 supervisors, and 3 operational coordinators.
- Processing of documentation and data entry into databases.
- Writing technical reports.
- o Daily reporting of incidents.

#### Researcher

Universidad Técnica de Ambato Ambato

Mar 2021 - Jan 2023

- Develop the state of the art of research projects.
- Develop research methodologies for investigative projects.
- Data collection and tabulation for research projects.
- Writing scientific articles.
- Translation of scientific articles into English.
- Bibliographic review of scientific articles, books, conferences, among others.

#### Technical Assistant

**FacGar** Ambato Apr 2013 - Oct 2013

- Customer service.
- Preventive and corrective maintenance of the vehicle's electrical system.
- Maintenance of electronic equipment.
- Installation and repair of car alarms.
- Design, construction and installation of Car Audio systems.
- Technical installer of car accessories.

## **Education**

Electronics and Communications Engineer

**Universidad Técnica de Ambato** Ambato Oct 2016 - Mar 2023

• Technical Bachelor in Electronics

**Instituto Superior Tecnológico Docente Guayaquil** *Ambato* Sep 2009 - Sep 2014

## **Certifications & Courses**

- Responsive Web Design freeCodeCamp. May 2023
- JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures. freeCodeCamp. Jun 2023
- Professional Web Development Course
   CódigoFacilito. Apr 2023
- Google Analytics Certification Google Digital Academy. Apr 2023
- Cloud Computing.
  Google Activate. *Mar 2023*
- Console Operator Eslaseg. Jul 2022

#### **Publications**

- Optimal stages of RF energy harvesting and storage systems. Enfoque UTE DOI: https://doi.org/10.29019/enfoqueute.883
- Hybrid Solar-Radiofrequency Energy Harvesting System for Fifth Generation 5G Terminals.

**Springer** DOI: 10.1007/978-3-031-24985-3\_1

• Effect of Slots in Rectangular Geometry Patch Antennas for Energy Harvesting in 2.4 GHz Band.

**Springer** DOI: 10.1007/978-3-031-30592-4\_22